A Guide to the Pete Calos Photograph Collection, 1977-2005
Library of Virginia
- Series IX: Works Progress Administration Post Office Murals., Extent: 1 cabinet. (Othertype 1)
  - Orange County Post Office: Upland Pastures - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:784)
  - Orange County Post Office: Upland Pastures, Horses - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:785)
  - Arlington Post Office - built 1937 - (Othertype 1:786)
  - Arlington Post Office - corner stone marker - (Othertype 1:787)
  - Arlington Post Office - front entrance - (Othertype 1:788)
  - Arlington Post Office - service windows - (Othertype 1:789)
  - Arlington Post Office: Picking Apples - mural - (Othertype 1:790)
  - Arlington Post Office: Playing Polo - mural - (Othertype 1:791)
  - Arlington Post Office: Picnicking - mural - (Othertype 1:792)
  - Arlington Post Office: Lee Accepting Command of the Armies of Virginia - mural - (Othertype 1:793)
  - Arlington Post Office: Slaves harvesting Tobacco - mural - (Othertype 1:794)
  - Arlington Post Office: Captain John Smith Meets Massawomeck Indians - mural - (Othertype 1:795)
  - Arlington Post Office: Indians preparing a meal - mural - (Othertype 1:796)
  - Berryville Post Office - exterior- (Othertype 1:797)
  - Berryville Post Office: Clarke County Products, 1939 - mural - (Othertype 1:798)
  - Berryville Post Office: Clarke County Products, 1939 - mural, detail of hunt dogs - (Othertype 1:799)
  - Berryville Post Office: Clarke County Products, 1939 - mural detail of farm animals - (Othertype 1:800)
  - Strasburg Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:801)
  - Strasburg Post Office: Apple Orchard - mural - (Othertype 1:802)
  - Strasburg Post Office: Apple Orchard - mural detail- (Othertype 1:803)
  - Strasburg Post Office: Apple Orchard - mural detail - (Othertype 1:804)
  - Luray Tower - exterior - (Othertype 1:805)
  - Luray Post Office: - built 1937 - exterior - (Othertype 1:806)
  - Luray Post Office: Luray 1840 - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:807)
  - Luray Post Office: Luray 1840 - detail of water pump, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:808)
  - Luray Post Office: Luray 1840 - detail ferrier, oil on canvas, detail ferrier - (Othertype 1:809)
  - Luray Post Office: Luray 1840 - detail of ferrier, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:810)
  - Luray Post Office: Luray 1840 - detail of horses, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:811)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office and Court House -exterior - (Othertype 1:812)
  - Harrisonburg Court House - front pediment - (Othertype 1:813)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - porch scene mural - (Othertype 1:814)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - carousel mural - (Othertype 1:815)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - movers mural - (Othertype 1:816)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - fountain mural- (Othertype 1:817)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of carousel - (Othertype 1:818)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of dancing - (Othertype 1:819)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of reading comics - (Othertype 1:820)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of mountain view - (Othertype 1:821)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of historic marker - (Othertype 1:822)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of freight handlers - (Othertype 1:823)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of market - (Othertype 1:824)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of couple with kids - (Othertype 1:825)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - artist William H. Calfee's signature - (Othertype 1:826)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of livestock sale - (Othertype 1:827)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of horse wrangler - (Othertype 1:828)
  - Harrisonburg Post Office: Country Fair, Trading Courthouse Square - detail of bull - (Othertype 1:829)
  - New Harrisonburg Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:830)
  - Staunton City Hall - exterior - (Othertype 1:831)
  - Staunton Post Office: Cyrus McCormick and the Reaper - terra cotta relief - (Othertype 1:832)
  - Staunton Post Office: Cyrus McCormick and the Reaper - detail of terra cotta relief - (Othertype 1:833)
  - Covington Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:834)
  - Altavista Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:835)
  - Altavista Post Office: The Growing Community - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:836)
  - Chatham Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:837)
  - Chatham Post Office: Harvest Season in Southern Virginia - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:838)
  - Chatham Post Office: Harvest Season in Southern Virginia - detail oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:839)
  - Chatham Post Office: Harvest Season in Southern Virginia - detail oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:840)
  - Franklin County Court House - exterior - (Othertype 1:841)
  - Rockymount Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:842)
  - Rockymount Post Office: Life in Rockymount - mural in situ- (Othertype 1:843)
  - Rockymount Post Office: Life in Rockymount - detail of haying - (Othertype 1:844)
  - Rockymount Post Office: Life in Rockymount - detail of weighing - (Othertype 1:845)
  - Rockymount Post Office: Life in Rockymount - detail of milling - (Othertype 1:846)
  - Bassett Furniture Company - exterior - (Othertype 1:847)
  - Bassett Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:848)
  - Bassett Post Office: Manufacturing of Furniture - fresco - (Othertype 1:849)
  - Bassett Post Office: Manufacturing of Furniture - fresco detail of worker - (Othertype 1:850)
  - Bassett Post Office: Manufacturing of Furniture - fresco detail of worker - (Othertype 1:851)
  - Bassett Post Office: Manufacturing of Furniture - fresc, detail of worker - (Othertype 1:852)
  - Stuart: Wood Brothers Garage - exterior - (Othertype 1:853)
  - Stuart Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:854)
  - Stuart Post Office - cornerstone - (Othertype 1:855)
  - Stuart Post Office - interior - (Othertype 1:856)
  - Stuart Post Office: Receiving Mail on the Farm - detail, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:857)
  - Stuart Post Office: Receiving Mail on the Farm - detail of family, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:858)
  - Stuart Post Office: Receiving Mail on the Farm - detail of mother & child, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:859)
  - Stuart Post Office: Receiving Mail on the Farm - detail of father & son, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:860)
  - Christiansburg Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:861)
  - Christiansburg Post Office: Great Road - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:862)
  - Christiansburg Post Office: Great Road - detail of soldiers, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:863)
  - Christiansburg Post Office: Great Road - detail of Frontier, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:864)
  - Christiansburg Post Office: Great Road - detail of Stagecoach, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:865)
  - Christiansburg Post Office: Great Road - detail artist John DeGroot's signature, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:866)
  - Radford Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:867)
  - Radford Post Office: Previous site of Mural - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:868)
  - Bluefield Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:869)
  - Bluefield Post Office: Interior - tempra mural - (Othertype 1:870)
  - Bluefield Post Office: Coal Mining - tempra mural - (Othertype 1:871)
  - Bluefield Post Office: Coal Mining - detail of blueprints, tempra mural - (Othertype 1:872)
  - Bluefield Post Office: Coal Mining - detail of blueprints, tempra mural - (Othertype 1:873)
  - Tazewell Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:874)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Sheep, Mother and Cow - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:875)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Sheep, Mother and Cow -detail, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:876)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Sheep, Mother and Cow - detail, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:877)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Mining - oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:878)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Mining - detail, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:879)
  - Tazewell Post Office: Mining -detail, oil on canvas - (Othertype 1:880)
  - Marion Diner, 1997 - exterior - (Othertype 1:881)
  - Marion Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:882)
  - The new Marion Post Office - exterior - (Othertype 1:883)
  - The new Marion Post Office - Packaged Murals waiting installation - (Othertype 1:884)
- Series X: Calos Compact Disc Collection. (Othertype 1)
  The Calos Compact Disc Collection includes mixed subjects photographed by Calos from 1996 to 2001 in counties across Virginia. Subjects include; abandoned homes, log cabins, Post Offices, schools, diners, stores, restaurants, bridges, views, hotels, taverns, theatres, barns, churches, cemeteries, courthouses, libraries, laundries, fire stations, railroad stations, service stations, drug stores, barber shops, and banks.
  Calos' original 35mm color transparencies were scanned at 300 dpi. A print index is available and the collection may be viewed in the Prints and Photographs Department, in Special Collections Monday through Friday from 9 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.